INNOVATIVE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Software engineer specializing in design, development and implementation of applications in C and C++ programming languages. Success based on knowledge of the software development cycle, data structures and ability to work with both local onsite teams and global partners to identify requirements, implement designs, and test the final product.

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- JQuery
- Responsive Design
- Bootstrap
- MERN Stack

- SQL
- Python
- GIT (Version Control Tracking System)
- C++ and C Programming
- Technical Writing
- Windows Batch scripting
- Linux CSH/KSH Shell Scripting

EXPERIENCE

LENOVO (IBM), Durham/Morrisville, NC Software Engineer

2007-2017

Designed, developed, and implemented tools for Linux and Windows in C and C++ to run third party command line tools used for firmware and BIOS updates, which allowed customers to efficiently update the software for their devices and improved customer experience.

- Used oral and written communication skills and interpersonal skills to collaborate with crossfunctional and international teams to resolve defects and achieve aggressive target dates for delivery of update packages to customers
- Worked directly with hardware engineers to identify application requirements. Efficient and effective communication that resulted in the delivery of tools on or ahead of schedule and met all expectations and functions.
- Prepared server systems and conducted unit testing and debugging of developed tools and programs before delivery test teams and during quality test cycles. Resulted in the reduction of issues identified during quality test cycles.
- Wrote and maintained technical training manual of the x86 Storage Options update packages building process, to facilitate peer training.
- Conducted video conference meetings for remote and international peers to train them to build update packages which has resulted in shorter build cycles and 50% reduction in documentation defects.
- Improved customer experience in two months' time by resolving a six-month back log of RAID update defects by making use of problem solving and analytical skills to debug root cause for each issue.

- In a timeframe of two months, resolved a six month of back log of RAID update defects by making use of problem solving and analytical skills to debug root cause for each issue.
- Maintained and troubleshot a vSphere CIM Provider for updating hard driver adapters, which improved customer experience by allowing customer to apply updates to their devices without shutting down the system's operating system.
- Designed, developed, and implemented update packages for RAID and HBA adapter products in support of Purley platform launch, while concurrently managing regular test cycles for prior existing test projects.
- Managed and designed storage Options update packages to be built by company partners.
 The company was able to provide warranty support of legacy System x servers after the divestiture.
- Managed publishing of x86 Storage Options update packages to external customer download site and maintained content pages, which increased customer satisfaction by providing direct links to latest device firmware and driver updates.
- Built quarterly software update support packages to support up to 40 hard drive controllers, backplanes and hard drive controller PSoC devices for System x and Flex, SAS and SATA hard drives.

DELL EMC, Research Triangle Park, NC

Technical Support Engineer 2

2018-Present

Provide technical support to customers for High-End Data Protection Storage System. Specialize in isolating or fixing filesystem, capacity and performance issues.

- Focus on providing a great customer experience satisfied.
- Responsible for providing telephone, email, and remote diagnostic technical support.
- Answer questions about installation, configuration, performance and usage of product features.
- Apply diagnostic techniques to identify problems, investigate causes and recommend solutions to correct failures.
- Document problems in the support solution database for diagnostics and solution implementation

IBM, Rochester, MN

I/T Specialist AIX System Administrator

2004 - 2007

Maintained a developer AIX AFS work station client image in charge operation system. Conducted security and other software updates, which allowed developers to focus their time and effort on the design of customer applications.

- Led weekly customer meetings to discuss and plan image changes for the following week.
- Participated in 24/7 administration support weekly on call rotation.
- Coordinated problem determination and resolution of issues within the client image.
- Completed both initial system setup and migration of existing systems to new hardware.
- Managed migration of AIX AFS workstation client image from AIX 5.1 to AIX 5.3.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

North Carolina Agricultural and Technical State University, Greensboro, NC

Certificate, Full Stack Web Developer

Coding Boot Camp at UNC Chapel Hill